{"categories":[{"name":"Bullying","questions":[{"questionText":"You are playing an online game and someone says something mean. Should you:","postQuestionText":"Ignore them and always tell an adult!","answers":[{"text":"Say something mean back","correct":false},{"text":"Ask them to to say sorry","correct":false},{"text":"Ignore them and tell an adult","correct":true},{"text":"None of the above","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"What are some of the risks of playing online games?","postQuestionText":"All of the above. Talk to an adult if any of these things happen to you whilst gaming.","answers":[{"text":"You may be bullied","correct":false},{"text":"You may be tricked into giving up in-game items","correct":false},{"text":"Some may try to ruin the game (a griefer)","correct":false},{"text":"All of the above","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"What is an online troll?","postQuestionText":"Someone who deliberately tries to ruin your online game or upset you for fun is a troll.","answers":[{"text":"A character from Lord of the Rings","correct":false},{"text":"A mythical animal","correct":false},{"text":"Someone who deliberately tries upset you","correct":true},{"text":"A glitch in your computer","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"While you are playing a game online you see the chat becoming nasty. What should you do?","postQuestionText":"You should ignore and report the chat or tell an adult if reporting is not an option. In some games, you can hide the chat instead.","answers":[{"text":"Tell them to stop","correct":false},{"text":"Join in with them","correct":false},{"text":"Ignore and report it","correct":true},{"text":"Never play the game again","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"In which of these do you think that you are most likely to be bullied?","postQuestionText":"Bullying is most common on social media, although bullying happens in all of these.","answers":[{"text":"Text","correct":false},{"text":"Social media","correct":true},{"text":"Email","correct":false},{"text":"Online games","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Name-calling is the most common form of online bullying. Where do you think this happens the most?","postQuestionText":"Online games and chats are the most common places you may be called names.","answers":[{"text":"Text","correct":false},{"text":"Social media","correct":false},{"text":"Email","correct":false},{"text":"Online games","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Do you think that boys or girls are more likely to be bullied online?","postQuestionText":"Boys are more likely to be bullied online.","answers":[{"text":"Boys","correct":true},{"text":"Girls","correct":false},{"text":"The same","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Which age group do you think is most likely to be bullied?","postQuestionText":"Out of these groups, 18-29 year olds are most likely to be bullied online.","answers":[{"text":"18-29","correct":true},{"text":"30-45","correct":false},{"text":"46-60","correct":false},{"text":"61\u002B","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"How often are young people bullied online?","postQuestionText":"Often. It is more common than you may think!","answers":[{"text":"Rarely","correct":false},{"text":"Sometimes","correct":false},{"text":"Never","correct":false},{"text":"Often","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Why are young people most likely to be bullied online?","postQuestionText":"Someone\u0027s skin colour or race are the most common reasons that people are bullied online.","answers":[{"text":"Because of their skin colour or race","correct":true},{"text":"Because of their opinions","correct":false},{"text":"For being a boy or a girl","correct":false},{"text":"For how they look","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"How would you help someone who is being bullied online?","postQuestionText":"All of these are all good ideas for helping a friend being bullied. Bullies often think they will get away with bullying online.","answers":[{"text":"Try to stop it","correct":false},{"text":"Speak to an adult","correct":false},{"text":"Report it online","correct":false},{"text":"Any of the above","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"You receive an email from an email address you do not recognise. What should you do?","postQuestionText":"Speaking to an adult is always the best option.","answers":[{"text":"Reply to the email","correct":false},{"text":"Speak to an adult","correct":true},{"text":"Delete and ignore it","correct":false},{"text":"Send it to a friend to look at","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Why should you report bullying online?","postQuestionText":"All of these are good reasons to report bullying.","answers":[{"text":"So the website can deal with it","correct":false},{"text":"Because they are not very nice","correct":false},{"text":"To try and stop the bullying","correct":false},{"text":"All of the above","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Will your friends find out if you report them for bullying online?","postQuestionText":"No, a website will not tell the bully who reported them.","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":false},{"text":"No","correct":true},{"text":"Maybe","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Is it ever okay to pretend to be another person online?","postQuestionText":"It is never okay to pretend to be another person online.","answers":[{"text":"Yes, if they are mean","correct":false},{"text":"No, it is never okay","correct":true},{"text":"Yes, it is funny","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, if they said I could","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Is it okay to make mean comments online, if you think it is funny?","postQuestionText":"It is never okay to make mean comments online. How would you feel if someone said mean things about you?","answers":[{"text":"Yes, if it is about someone mean","correct":false},{"text":"No, never","correct":true},{"text":"Yes, if it is to a stranger","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, if they don\u0027t know it is from me","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"If you make mean comments about someone online, what might happen?","postQuestionText":"All of the above! It is never okay to make mean comments about other people online.","answers":[{"text":"They may be upset or angry","correct":false},{"text":"You might be blocked","correct":false},{"text":"You could lose friends","correct":false},{"text":"All of the above","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"A friends tells you that somebody has been calling them mean names on an online game. What should you do?","postQuestionText":"Calling somebody mean names online is cyberbullying. You should tell an adult about it and not ignore it.","answers":[{"text":"Tell them to call the person mean names back","correct":false},{"text":"Tell your teacher or another adult","correct":true},{"text":"Tell them to ignore it until they stop","correct":false},{"text":"Tell them to stop playing games for a while","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Is it ever acceptable to create a fake profile for someone you know as a prank?","postQuestionText":"IT IS ABSOLUTELY NEVER ACCEPTABLE TO MAKE A FAKE PROFILE FOR SOMEONE ELSE.","answers":[{"text":"Yes, if I do not like them","correct":false},{"text":"No, it is never acceptable","correct":true},{"text":"Yes, if you think they will find it funny","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, if they never find out","correct":false}]}]},{"name":"Information","questions":[{"questionText":"A game you are playing tells you to buy more coins. What should you do?","postQuestionText":"Always check with an adult before buying anything online.","answers":[{"text":"Buy them straight away","correct":false},{"text":"Check with an adult first","correct":true},{"text":"Delete the game","correct":false},{"text":"Check with your friends first","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"True or false: If I delete something online, it will never be seen again.","postQuestionText":"False. Online posts can last forever! You never know if someone else has already copied or shared your post.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Is it okay to share personal information online?","postQuestionText":"Never reveal personal information, be wary of who is asking for it and tell a parent or teacher.","answers":[{"text":"Yes, it\u2019s fun to share","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, to people who seem friendly","correct":false},{"text":"No, never reveal personal information","correct":true},{"text":"Yes, if my friends think it is okay","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"You are on a new website. Should you enter your name and phone number to enter a contest?","postQuestionText":"No, never share your details online without checking with an adult first.","answers":[{"text":"No, always check with an adults before sharing details","correct":true},{"text":"Yes, if the website is pretty","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, it\u0027s only my name and number","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, you might win something","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Should you shares photos of yourself online?","postQuestionText":"No, it is never a good idea to post photos of yourself online.","answers":[{"text":"No, never","correct":true},{"text":"Yes, if you look nice","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, if it\u0027s to people you know","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, if my friends are doing it too","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"If a game asks you to sign up to play. What should you do?","postQuestionText":"Always check with an adult before signing up to anything online.","answers":[{"text":"Sign up straight away","correct":false},{"text":"Check whether my friends have signed up too","correct":false},{"text":"Enter somebody else\u0027s details","correct":false},{"text":"Check with an adult before you sign up","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"If you see something online that you want to buy, should you use your parents card to buy it?","postQuestionText":"You should always check with an adult before buying anything online, even if you really want it.","answers":[{"text":"Yes, if I have already told my parents I want it","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, if it is cheap","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, I will pay my parents back","correct":false},{"text":"No, always check with an adult first","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"What could happen if you share your passwords with your friends?","postQuestionText":"They could do any of these! Never share your passwords with anyone.","answers":[{"text":"They could get into my account and use it","correct":false},{"text":"They could change my details and lock me out","correct":false},{"text":"They could give my details to someone else","correct":false},{"text":"Any of the above","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Should you sign up to a game that offers you a free trial?","postQuestionText":"No, always check with an adult first. You will have to pay when the free trial ends.","answers":[{"text":"Yes, the trial is free!","correct":false},{"text":"No, check with an adult before signing up to anything","correct":true},{"text":"Yes, if it\u0027s for less than a week","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, if my friends are doing it","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"How do you know what you should share online?","postQuestionText":"It is best not to share any details about yourself or your friends online. You never know who will see it.","answers":[{"text":"Ask your best friend","correct":false},{"text":"You should not share any details about yourself online","correct":true},{"text":"Only what everyone else is sharing","correct":false},{"text":"Whatever you want to share","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"What you should do if you receive text messages from a stranger?","postQuestionText":"You should always tell an adult if you are receiving messages from someone you don\u0027t know. Do not respond to the messages.","answers":[{"text":"Reply if they seem nice","correct":false},{"text":"Ignore them and delete the messages","correct":false},{"text":"Tell your friends","correct":false},{"text":"Show an adult","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Should you always use the same passwords?","postQuestionText":"No, you should always use different passwords for everything to keep your accounts safe.","answers":[{"text":"Yes, so I can remember them","correct":false},{"text":"No, I should always use different passwords","correct":true},{"text":"It depends what for","correct":false},{"text":"Only for important things","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Your friend asks to use your computer for their school work. Should you give your password to them?","postQuestionText":"No, you must always keep your passwords a secret.","answers":[{"text":"Yes, I trust them","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, if they can help me with my homework too","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, if they promise not to share it with anyone else","correct":false},{"text":"No, you should never share it","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"What happens to my accounts if I stop using them?","postQuestionText":"Your accounts and everything you have shared on them will still be there, even if you stop using them. ","answers":[{"text":"They disappear","correct":false},{"text":"They stay the same","correct":true},{"text":"They get deleted","correct":false},{"text":"They are taken over by aliens","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Which of these are safe to share online?","postQuestionText":"None of the above. You should never share any personal information, like where you live or go to school. You never know who will see it!","answers":[{"text":"A picture of your school","correct":false},{"text":"A picture of yourself","correct":false},{"text":"A picture of your house","correct":false},{"text":"None of the above","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"If someone asks you to send a picture or video of yourself to them, what should you do?","postQuestionText":"Sometimes people online might try to trick you into sharing pictures or videos of yourself. Tell an adult if this happens and remember,  never share pictures of yourself or videos with anyone online. ","answers":[{"text":"Send one, if you have been talking to them for a while and they are nice","correct":false},{"text":"Do not send one, always check with an adult before sending a video or picture of yourself to anyone","correct":true},{"text":"Send one, if they promise not to share it with anyone else","correct":false},{"text":"Send one, if my friends are sharing pictures of themselves as well","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Is it true that someone could access your webcam without you knowing?","postQuestionText":"Yes, there are viruses that will allow someone to access your webcam without you knowing. Keep your webcam covered when you are not using it.","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":true},{"text":"No","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Your friend sends you a link to a website with a strange name, should you click it?","postQuestionText":"No, always check with an adult first. It may be someone pretending to be your friend and the link may contain a virus.","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":false},{"text":"No","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"You have made a new friend online and they ask for your email address to send you a funny video, what should you do?","postQuestionText":"Never share your details with anyone that you have only met online, always check with an adult","answers":[{"text":"Share your email in a chat","correct":false},{"text":"Ask them to send you their email in a chat","correct":false},{"text":"Ask them what the video is of first","correct":false},{"text":"Check with an adult before sharing your email address","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Is it better to use a screen name or your real name?","postQuestionText":"You should not use your real name online. It is a good idea to choose a screen name that does not include your first or last name, or any other information, such as your age or birthday.","answers":[{"text":"Your real name","correct":false},{"text":"A screen name","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"What is the minimum age for most social networking sites?","postQuestionText":"Most social media websites have a minimum age of 13 years old, but you should check the age rating of each app to make sure.","answers":[{"text":"7","correct":false},{"text":"10","correct":false},{"text":"13","correct":true},{"text":"16","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"You need to make a password for a website. What should you use?","postQuestionText":"The best passwords have a mix of letters, numbers and symbols. You should never use your name or birthday, as this makes it easy to guess.","answers":[{"text":"Your full name","correct":false},{"text":"A nickname that your friends call you","correct":false},{"text":"Part of your name and your age or birthday","correct":false},{"text":"A mix of letters, numbers and symbols.","correct":true}]}]},{"name":"Privacy","questions":[{"questionText":"What picture tells you that a website is safe?","postQuestionText":"A padlock, which can be found next to the search bar.","answers":[{"text":"A shield","correct":false},{"text":"A padlock","correct":true},{"text":"A star","correct":false},{"text":"A house","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"How many passwords should you have?","postQuestionText":"You should use different password for every account. If you have the same password for every account and somebody guesses it, they then have access to all of your accounts!","answers":[{"text":"One \u2013 so I can remember it","correct":false},{"text":"Two \u2013 one for important accounts and one for others","correct":false},{"text":"Five or six \u2013 to change between","correct":false},{"text":"A different password for every account","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"How do you know if someone else is using your account?","postQuestionText":"You might not always know if someone has your details, so it is a good idea to change your passwords often.","answers":[{"text":"Your picture changes","correct":false},{"text":"Your name changes","correct":false},{"text":"You get lots of messages","correct":false},{"text":"You might not know someone is using your account","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"How often are passwords stolen?","postQuestionText":"Passwords are stolen very often, more often than you may think!","answers":[{"text":"Rarely","correct":false},{"text":"Sometimes","correct":false},{"text":"Often","correct":false},{"text":"Very often","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"A gaming website asks you to download something before playing. What should you do?","postQuestionText":"Stop and think before you click any links, always check with an adult first.","answers":[{"text":"Ask your friend to download it instead","correct":false},{"text":"Click the link if a friend sent it to you","correct":false},{"text":"Check with an adult first","correct":true},{"text":"Download it and find out","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Why do your parents control what you can do online?","postQuestionText":"Your parents control your internet use to keep you safe. The internet can be a dangerous place.","answers":[{"text":"To ruin your fun","correct":false},{"text":"To annoy you","correct":false},{"text":"To keep you safe","correct":true},{"text":"To punish you","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"If your friend asks to borrow your computer, what should you do?","postQuestionText":"Check with an adult before you let anyone else use your computer.","answers":[{"text":"Check with an adult first","correct":true},{"text":"Watch them while they use it","correct":false},{"text":"Let them borrow it","correct":false},{"text":"Tell them to be careful","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"True or false: my friends cannot post pictures of me online.","postQuestionText":"False: nobody else should post pictures of you online but you cannot be sure that they wont. Tell an adult straight away if someone posts a picture of you online.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"How can you check your social media safety settings?","postQuestionText":"Log out or go onto another device and search for you on google or social media to see if your safety settings are working.","answers":[{"text":"Look at your social media from another device","correct":true},{"text":"You don\u0027t need to check them","correct":false},{"text":"You can\u0027t","correct":false},{"text":"Ask a friend to take a look","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"True or false: you will always know straight away if a virus is on your computer.","postQuestionText":"False. It is not always easy to determine if your computer has been affected by a virus.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"What should you do if you see a pop-up on a website?","postQuestionText":"Always check with an adult before clicking on any pop-ups.","answers":[{"text":"Click it straight away","correct":false},{"text":"Check with an adult","correct":true},{"text":"Ignore it","correct":false},{"text":"Throw your computer away","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"If you see a padlock by the search bar, what does that mean?","postQuestionText":"A padlock means the website is safe.","answers":[{"text":"The website is unsafe","correct":false},{"text":"The website is blocked","correct":false},{"text":"The website is safe","correct":true},{"text":"The website needs unlocking","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"What is \u0027airplane mode\u0027 on a phone?","postQuestionText":"A setting that means your phone cannot get signal or use the internet.","answers":[{"text":"A picture of an airplane on your phone","correct":false},{"text":"A setting for safe internet surfing","correct":false},{"text":"A plug in that charges the phone","correct":false},{"text":"A setting that means your phone cannot get signal or use the internet","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"A website you want to access has an age restriction and you are not old enough, do you?","postQuestionText":"Leave the site. The age restriction is there to protect you.","answers":[{"text":"Lie about your age so you can access the website","correct":false},{"text":"Leave the website","correct":true},{"text":"Pretend to be a family member who is older","correct":false},{"text":"Report the website","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"You see an advert online which tells you that you have won a new iPhone! You click it and it asks for your details. What should you do?","postQuestionText":"Don\u0027t enter any details. The advert is trying to get you to enter your information and they may have bad intentions. There is no iPhone for you to win.","answers":[{"text":"Do not enter any details, the advert may be trying to trick you into sharing your personal information.","correct":true},{"text":"Enter all of your details, it is a free iPhone afterall!","correct":false}]}]},{"name":"Relationships","questions":[{"questionText":"Is it easy to know if someone you met online is a nice person?","postQuestionText":"It is not always easy to know if someone is a nice person, or they may be pretending. Always check with an adult before speaking to someone.","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":false},{"text":"No","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Someone you talk to online wants to meet you in-person to hang out. What should you do?","postQuestionText":"Never meet someone you have met online, and always speak to an adult before speaking to someone new online.","answers":[{"text":"If you trust them, meet them","correct":false},{"text":"Take a friend with you","correct":false},{"text":"Invite them to your house","correct":false},{"text":"Do not meet with them","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"You don\u0027t have lots of online friends. What should you do?","postQuestionText":"Only add people you know to your accounts - it does not matter how many friends you have online. Never add strangers online.","answers":[{"text":"Add everyone you can find","correct":false},{"text":"Tell people to add you","correct":false},{"text":"Delete your accounts","correct":false},{"text":"Only add people you know","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Someone you speak to online wants to meet in real life. Is it ok for you to go and meet them?","postQuestionText":"No - never meet up with people you don\u0027t know in real life and tell an adult.","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":false},{"text":"No","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"If your online friend asks you to do them a favour, what should you do?","postQuestionText":"Always tell an adult if a stranger is messaging you online.","answers":[{"text":"Do what they ask","correct":false},{"text":"Find out what the favour is","correct":false},{"text":"Tell your friends","correct":false},{"text":"Tell an adult","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Who should you believe online?","postQuestionText":"You can\u0027t always trust that what people are sharing online is true.","answers":[{"text":"Everyone","correct":false},{"text":"My online friends","correct":false},{"text":"YouTubers","correct":false},{"text":"None of the above","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Should you accept a friend request from someone famous?","postQuestionText":"No, you should never add anyone you do not know in real life. They may be someone else pretending to be a celebrity.","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":false},{"text":"No","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Is it okay to post a picture of you and a friend online?","postQuestionText":"No, you should never share pictures of your or your friends online.","answers":[{"text":"Yes, if it is a nice picture","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, if I took the picture","correct":false},{"text":"No, never upload pictures of anyone else","correct":true},{"text":"Yes, if they say it is okay","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"How can you find out how old someone you are talking to online is?","postQuestionText":"You can\u2019t know for sure, they may lie or they could be pretending to be someone else.","answers":[{"text":"Check their profile","correct":false},{"text":"Guess based on their pictures","correct":false},{"text":"Just ask them","correct":false},{"text":"You can\u0027t know for sure","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"You film your friend throwing stones at cars and post it on TikTok. Is this okay?","postQuestionText":"No, filming someone doing something silly or against the rules may seem cool but it could get you both in trouble.","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":false},{"text":"No","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Will you always be able to delete your old posts online?","postQuestionText":"No, anyone could have saved your posts or shared them elsewhere.","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":false},{"text":"No","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"How do you know it is really your friend following you on TikTok?","postQuestionText":"You can never been sure, check with your friends in real life before adding them.","answers":[{"text":"We have the same friends","correct":false},{"text":"It has videos of them","correct":false},{"text":"You can never be sure","correct":true},{"text":"It uses their name","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"What is \u0027fake news\u0027?","postQuestionText":"Fake news is made up or misleading news that appears to be real. Always check with an adult.","answers":[{"text":"Old news","correct":false},{"text":"Made up news","correct":true},{"text":"Good news","correct":false},{"text":"Boring","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Should you share interesting facts you have seen online?","postQuestionText":"No, you never know if information you read online is actually true, always check with an adult.","answers":[{"text":"Yes, if it is funny","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, if it appears to be real","correct":false},{"text":"Only if your friends are sharing it too","correct":false},{"text":"No, always check with an adult","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Why do some websites have an age limit?","postQuestionText":"Because some content on the website might not be suitable for children.","answers":[{"text":"Because some content might not be suitable for children","correct":true},{"text":"To make it more interesting for children","correct":false},{"text":"So you lie about your age","correct":false},{"text":"To stop you and your friends having fun","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Your friend tells you that they are talking to a new friend online and they are going to meet them at the weekend. What should you do?","postQuestionText":"Tell an adult straight away if somebody going to meet a person that they met online. You should never meet people unless you know who they are for certain.","answers":[{"text":"Offer to go with them","correct":false},{"text":"Let them go alone","correct":false},{"text":"Tell an adult straight away","correct":true},{"text":"Ask your friends for their advice","correct":false}]}]},{"name":"Wellbeing","questions":[{"questionText":"What is the best way to know whether a video game is suitable for a you?","postQuestionText":"Always check with an adult before downloading and playing a new game. ","answers":[{"text":"Ask you friends what they think","correct":false},{"text":"Play the game to find out","correct":false},{"text":"Check what age it says on the box","correct":false},{"text":"Check with an adult","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"If a game says it for 7 year olds and above, is it safe to play?","postQuestionText":"No, it may not always be safe for you to play. Check with an adult who knows you well.","answers":[{"text":"Yes, it is totally safe","correct":false},{"text":"No, it may not always be safe","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"If a game has a cute picture on the front, is it safe to play?","postQuestionText":"No, it may not always be safe for you to play. Check with an adult who knows you well.","answers":[{"text":"Yes, it is totally safe","correct":false},{"text":"No, it may not always be safe","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Should you \u0027go live\u0027 on Tik Tok?","postQuestionText":"No, you should never go live on Tik Tok. You do not know who may be watching.","answers":[{"text":"Yes, it is fun","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, if my friends want to watch","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, if my parents are home","correct":false},{"text":"No, you should never go live","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Could videos and pictures that look real actually be fake?","postQuestionText":"Yes, people can easily make fake pictures of anything or anyone.","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":true},{"text":"No","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"A friend uploads a silly picture of you online that you do not like, what should you do?","postQuestionText":"Always tell an adult, and ask your friend to delete the picture.","answers":[{"text":"Tell an adult and ask your friend to delete it","correct":true},{"text":"Post a picture of your friend as well","correct":false},{"text":"Block them and ask all your friends to as well","correct":false},{"text":"Nothing, my friends think it is funny","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Can you spend too much time watching TikTok?","postQuestionText":"Yes you can. If it is making you feel sad or tired and distracting you from doing other things.","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":true},{"text":"No","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"What is an influencer?","postQuestionText":"Someone with lots of followers, and they may suggest things for you to buy. They may be getting paid to do this.","answers":[{"text":"Friends who try to get me to post silly videos","correct":false},{"text":"The person who owns TikTok","correct":false},{"text":"Someone who makes big decisions","correct":false},{"text":"Someone with lots of followers, and shares their life online","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"What should you do if something online makes you feel sad?","postQuestionText":"You should come offline for a while and talk to an adult about what you are feeling. You may want to delete the apps that are making you feel that way and take part in some other activities that you enjoy instead.","answers":[{"text":"Share my feelings online","correct":false},{"text":"Talk to your friends about it","correct":false},{"text":"Take some time away and talk to an adult","correct":true},{"text":"Ignore it and keep scrolling","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"If someone is pretending to be you online, what should you do?","postQuestionText":"After reporting the account, warn everyone who may want to add the account and show an adult. ","answers":[{"text":"Report the account and show an adult","correct":true},{"text":"Add them so you can see what they are doing","correct":false},{"text":"Tell your friends about it","correct":false},{"text":"Message them and tell them stop","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"What is an in-game purchase?","postQuestionText":"A real purchase within a game. This means you are spending real money. Always check with an adult before making an in-game purchase.","answers":[{"text":"An online shop","correct":false},{"text":"When you buy a game on Amazon","correct":false},{"text":"A fake purchase within a game","correct":false},{"text":"A real purchase within a game","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Should you be able to do everything that your friends can do online?","postQuestionText":"No, everyone family has different rules. Always talk to an adult to check what is okay for you.","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":false},{"text":"No","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Someone you do not know sends you a friend request, what should you do?","postQuestionText":"Check with an adult first","answers":[{"text":"Accept if you like the name","correct":false},{"text":"Accept if they sound nice","correct":false},{"text":"Check with an adult first","correct":true},{"text":"Accept but do not speak to them","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Your parents or an adult you trust want to be your friend online, is that a good idea?","postQuestionText":"Yes, it is always a good idea to have your parents or an adult you trust as your friend so they can  help you stay safe online.","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":true},{"text":"No","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Someone in your class has sent around an embarrassing photo of another classmate. What should you do with it?","postQuestionText":"Show an adult you trust. Imagine how you would feel if it was an embarrassing photo of you.","answers":[{"text":"Forward the photo onto other people if it\u0027s funny","correct":false},{"text":"Show an adult you trust and explain what has happened","correct":true},{"text":"Save it to your phone to show people when you want","correct":false},{"text":"Laugh at the photo with your friends","correct":false}]}]}]}